export const CHEMISTRYA2016 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The following atoms of carbon 126C, 136C and 146C can be described as?",
A: "Allotropes",
B: "Isomers",
C: "Isotopes",
D: "Isotones",
answer: "C. Isotopes",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. An atom X consist of 6 protons, 6 electrons and 7 neutrons. Which of the following representations of the atom is correct?",
A: "13 6X",
B: "13 7X",
C: "19 6X",
D: "19 7X",
answer: "A. 136X",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. How many electrons are present in 94Be2+?",
A: "2",
B: "4",
C: "5",
D: "6",
answer: "A. 2",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. When element 20Y combines with element 8Z, it forms",
A: "A covalent compound, YZ is formed",
B: "A covalent compound, ZY is formed",
C: "An ionic compound, YZ is formed",
D: "An ionic compound, ZY is formed",
answer: "C. An ionic compound, YZ is formed",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The boiling points of HF, H2O and NH3 increase in the order of",
A: "NH3",
B: "H2O < HF",
C: "HF < NH3 < H2O",
D: "NH3 < HF < H2O",
answer: "D. NH3 < HF < H2O",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Chemicals that are produced in small quantities and with very degree of purity are",
A: "Bulk chemicals",
B: "Fine chemicals",
C: "Heavy chemicals",
D: "Light chemicals",
answer: "B. Fine chemicals",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The mass of potassium hydroxide required to make 300.ocm3 of 0.4 moldm-3 solution is {KOH = 56.0}",
A: "26.88g",
B: "13.44g",
C: "6.72g",
D: "3.36g",
answer: "C. 6.72g",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Metals can be stretched into wires because they are",
A: "Ductile",
B: "Good conductors",
C: "Lustrous",
D: "Malleable",
answer: "A. Ductile",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Aluminum is used in the manufacture or aircraft because it",
A: "Is hard and brittle",
B: "Is light and resists corrosion",
C: "Has high density and conducts electricity",
D: "Is malleable and ductile",
answer: "B. Is light and resists corrosion",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. An unsaturated solution differs from a saturated solution at a given temperature because it",
A: "Cannot dissolve more solute",
B: "Can hold more solute than it can actually dissolve",
C: "Can still dissolve more solute at given temperature",
D: "Form crystal more easily on cooling",
answer: "C. Can still dissolve more solute at given temperature",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Which of the following arrangements shows increasing order of reactivity of the halogens?",
A: "F2 > Cl2 > Br2 >I2",
B: "I2 < Br2 < Cl2",
C: "F2 < Cl2 < Br2",
D: "I2 > Br2 > Cl2 > F2",
answer: "B. I2 > Br2 > Cl2",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The shape of the water molecule is_______?",
A: "Linear",
B: "Pyramidal",
C: "Tetrahedral",
D: "V-shaped",
answer: "D. V-shaped",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of the following elements would produce coloured ion in aqueous solution?",
A: "Calcium",
B: "Copper",
C: "Magnesium",
D: "Sodium",
answer: "B. Copper",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The minimum amount of energy required for effective collisions between reacting particles is known as",
A: "Activation energy",
B: "Bond energy",
C: "Kinetic energy",
D: "Potential energy",
answer: "A. Activation energy",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The bond formed between H2O and H+ to form the hydroxonium H3O+ is",
A: "Dative",
B: "Covalent",
C: "Electrovalent",
D: "Ionic",
answer: "A. Dative",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. An element X forms the following oxides X2O, XO and XO2. This phenomenon illustrates the law of________?",
A: "Conservation of mass",
B: "Definite proportion",
C: "Mass action",
D: "Multiple proportion",
answer: "D. Multiple proportion",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. How many moles of oxygen would contain 1.204 x 1024 molecules? [Avogadro's constant (NA) = 6.02 x 1023]",
A: "1",
B: "2",
C: "3",
D: "4",
answer: "B.2",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Which of the following statements about solids is correct?",
A: "Solid particles are less orderly than those of a liquid",
B: "Solid have lower densities than liquids",
C: "Solid particles have greater kinetic energies than those of liquids",
D: "Solid particles cannot be easily compressed",
answer: "D. Solid particles cannot be easily compressed",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the following apparatus can be used to measure a specific volume of a liquid accurately?",
A: "Beaker",
B: "Conical flask",
C: "Measuring cylinder",
D: "Pipette",
answer: "D. Pipette",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The general gas equation PV / T = K is a combination of",
A: "Boyle's and Charles' laws",
B: "Boyle's and Graham's laws",
C: "Charles' and Graham's laws",
D: "Dalton's and Graham's laws",
answer: "Z. ZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZ",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The spreading of the scent of a flower in a garden is an example of_____?",
A: "Brownian motion",
B: "Diffusion",
C: "Osmosis",
D: "Tynadal effect",
answer: "B. Diffusion",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Propane carbon (IV)oxide diffuse at the same rate because [H = 1.00, C = 12.0, O = 16.0]",
A: "They are both gases",
B: "Their molecules contain carbon",
C: "They have the same relative molecular mass",
D: "Both are denser than air",
answer: "C. They have the same relative molecular mass",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The energy which accompanies the addition of an electron to an isolated gaseous atom is",
A: "Atomization",
B: "Electronegativity",
C: "Electron affinity",
D: "Ionization",
answer: "B. Electronegativity",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. An aqueous solution of (NH4)2 SO4 is",
A: "Acidic",
B: "Alkaline",
C: "Amphoteric",
D: "Neutral",
answer: "A. Acidic",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. When NH4Cl(s) is dissolved in water, the container feels cold to touch. This implies",
A: "The process is endothermic",
B: "The process is exothermic",
C: "NH4Cl forms a saturated solution",
D: "NH4Cl is highly soluble in water",
answer: "A. The process is endothermic",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The pH of four solutions M,N,Q and R are 2,6,8 and 11 respectively. Which of the following deductions about the solutions is correct?",
A: "The pH of N is increased when the solution is diluted",
B: "The pH of Q is increased when the solution is evaporated",
C: "M is the most alkaline solution",
D: "R is the most acidic solution",
answer: "A. The pH of N is increased when the solution is diluted",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Consider the following reaction equation H3O+(aq) + OH(aq) → 2H2O(1) The reaction represents",
A: "Esterification",
B: "Hydrolysis",
C: "Neutralization",
D: "Redox",
answer: "D. Redox",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The refreshing characteristic taste of fizzy drinks is due to the presence of",
A: "Carbon(IV)oxide",
B: "Glucose",
C: "Hydrogen",
D: "Sodium Citrate",
answer: "A. Carbon(IV)oxide",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Chemical equilibrium is attained when",
A: "All the reactants have been completely used up",
B: "The reaction goes to completion",
C: "The concentration of reactants and products remain constant",
D: "The concentration of reactants and products are equal",
answer: "C. The concentration of reactants and products remain constant",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which of the following factors will affect the rate of the reaction represented by the following equation? 2HCl(aq) + CaCO3(s) → CaCl2(aq) + H2O(1) + CO2(g) \nI. Pressure \nII. Concentration \nIII. Nature of reactants \nIV. Temperature",
A: "I and II only",
B: "II, III and IV only",
C: "I, II and III only",
D: "I, II. III and IV",
answer: "B. II, III and IV only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. On evaporation to dryness, 3503 of saturated solution of salt Z gave 55.5g of salt. What is the solubility of the salt? [Z = 101]",
A: "1.57 moldm-3",
B: "3.14 moldm-3",
C: "6.28 moldm-3",
D: "12.56 moldm-3",
answer: "A. 1.57 moldm-3",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Which of the following salts when dissolved in water will form a solution that will change blue litmus to red?",
A: "CH3COONa",
B: "NH4Cl",
C: "NaCl",
D: "KCl",
answer: "B. NH4Cl",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following bonds are broken when ethanol is boiled? \nI. Covalent bonds \nII. Ionic bonds \nIII. Hydrogen bonds",
A: "I only",
B: "II only",
C: "III only",
D: "I, II, III",
answer: "C. III only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. A compound with molecular formula CH2O2 is",
A: "A Carbohydrate",
B: "A Carboxylic acid",
C: "An alkanol",
D: "An ester",
answer: "B. A Carboxylic acid",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The quality of electricity required to discharge 1 mole of univalent ion is",
A: "9600C",
B: "48250C",
C: "96500C",
D: "193000C",
answer: "C. 96500C",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Chlorine water is used as a bleaching agent because it is",
A: "An acidic solution",
B: "An alkaline solution",
C: "An oxidizing agent",
D: "A reducing agent",
answer: "C. An oxidizing agent",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Which of the following substances is a non-electrolyte?",
A: "H2SO4",
B: "CH3COOH",
C: "C6H12O6",
D: "NH4Cl",
answer: "C. C6H12O6",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The oxidation number of Sulphur is +4 in",
A: "Na2S2O3",
B: "H2SO3",
C: "H2SO4",
D: "SO3",
answer: "B. H2SO3",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Consider the following ionic equation: Cr2O72- + 14H+ + ne- → 2Cr3+ + 7H2O. The value of n in the equation is_______?",
A: "7",
B: "6",
C: "3",
D: "2",
answer: "B. 6",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Consider the following half-cell reactions. Al(s) → Al3+(aq) + 3e- Cu2+(aq) + 2e- → Cu(s) The overall equation for the reaction is",
A: "Al(s) + Cu2+(aq) → Al3+(aq) + Cu(s)",
B: "2Al(s) + Cu2+(aq) → 2Al(aq) + Cu(s)",
C: "2Al(s) + 3Cu2+(aq) → 3Cu(s) + 2Al3+(aq)",
D: "3Al(s) + 2Cu2+(aq) → Cu(s) + 3Al3+(aq)",
answer: "C. 2Al(s) + 3Cu2+(aq) → 3Cu(s) + 2Al3+(aq)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Amino acids are obtained from proteins by",
A: "Hydrolysis",
B: "Oxidation",
C: "Polymerization",
D: "Reduction",
answer: "A. Hydrolysis",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. When a compound X is heated with concentrated tetraoxosulphate(VI)acid, it produces an alkene. X is an",
A: "Alkane",
B: "Alkanol",
C: "Alkanoate",
D: "Alkyne",
answer: "B. Alkanol",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Ripening of fruits is hastened by using",
A: "Ethanol",
B: "Ethane",
C: "Ethene",
D: "Ethyne",
answer: "C. Ethene",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. The compound that makes palm wine taste sour after exposure to the air for few days is",
A: "Ethanol",
B: "Ethanoic acid",
C: "Methanol",
D: "Methanoic acid",
answer: "B. Ethanoic acid",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Which of the following compounds is/are secondary alkanols? \ni) CH3CH(CH3)CH3OH \nii) CH3CH2CH(OH)CH3 \niii) CH3C(OH)(CH3)CH3",
A: "I only",
B: "II only",
C: "I and III only",
D: "II and III only",
answer: "B. II only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Consider the following reaction equation C2H4(g) + 3O2(g) → 2CO2(g) + 2H2O(l). The volume of oxygen at s.t.p that will be required to burn 14g of ethene is [C2H4 = 28; Molar volume of gas at s.t.p = 22.4dm3",
A: "64.2dm3",
B: "33.6dm3",
C: "11.2dm3",
D: "3.73dm3",
answer: "B. 33.6dm3",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Which of the following sources of energy contributes to green-house effect?",
A: "Natural gas",
B: "Nuclear",
C: "Wind",
D: "Solar",
answer: "A. Natural gas",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. A consequence of global warming is",
A: "Air pollution",
B: "Flooding",
C: "Increased humidity",
D: "Water pollution",
answer: "B. Flooding",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Which of the following metals is common to both brass and bronze?",
A: "Aluminum",
B: "Copper",
C: "Lead",
D: "Iron",
answer: "B. Copper",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The alkanol obtained from the production of soap is",
A: "Dihydric Alkanol",
B: "Tertiary Alkanol",
C: "Trihydric Alkanol",
D: "Monohydric Alkanol",
answer: "C. Trihydric Alkanol",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]